MOHAMED ALMAHDY

Mobile Applications Developer

- @ engmohamedalmahdy@gmail.com
- **+201096475710**
- Nasr City, Cairo
- LightFeather42

- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/eng-mohamed-almahdy
- https://github.com/eng-mohamedalmahdy

PROFILE

Mid-level Mobile Apps Engineer with **2+ years** of hands-on experience in Kotlin, Java, and Swift. Successfully developed and delivered **10+ mobile apps** across Native Android, iOS, and Kotlin Multiplatform (KMP) in **3+ companies**. Possess solid knowledge in digital marketing, enhancing overall versatility.

EXPERIENCE

Mid Level Android developer | DTag

04/2023 - Present

- Created & Contributed at 3 Mobile Apps:
 - Whizzy.
 - Samoolah For User & Agent.

JR. Software developer | Virtual Worker Now

12/2021 - 5/2022

- 2 Websites contributions & 2 Mobile Apps contributions
 - Pet Materices
 - Virtual Worker Now
 - Virtual Courses Now

JR. Android developer | ElMnassa Innovation

i 6/2020 - 12/2020

• 2 Mobile Apps contributions

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

 $\left(\mathsf{Kotlin} \right) \left(\mathsf{Java} \right) \left(\mathsf{Swift} \right)$

FRAMEWORKS

Native Android Kotlin Multiplatform

Native iOS

ANDROID TOOLS

Kotlin Compose | Coroutines | Retrofit

Rx Java & Kotlin Image Loaders

Koin Room Realm Dagger hilt

JUnit MocKK Mockito

IOS TOOLS

Ulkit Storyboard Auto layout

Swift UI) GCD RX Swift & Cocoa

Core Data Alamofire Kingfisher

SKILLS

- Strong grasp of **OOP**, data structures, and algorithms.
- Proficient in applying architecture patterns such as MVVM.
- Good understanding of design patterns & SOLID principles.
- Solid understanding of HTTP Requests and RESTful APIs.
- Experienced in creating and executing thorough Unit testing.
- Skilled in multithreading, & libraries like Coroutines & GCD.
- Proficient in applying Dependency Injection principle.
- Experience in other programming paradigms such as **Fp** & **Rx**.
- Expertise in version control systems such as Git and GitHub.
- Proficient in Gradle buildSrc & Plugins and catalog versions.

EDUCATION

B.S Computer Engineering | Al-Azhar University.

i 2017 - 2021

• Graduation Project: Zakerly (E-learning Mobile App) Grade : Excellent

RECENT BOOKS READINGS

- Clean Mobile Arch.
- Algorithms Unplugged
- Gradle for Android

- Clean Arch.
- Head First OOA/D
- My book list: HERE

Android Projects

Samoolah 🔒 📥

- Services Provider App With 2 Distributions 1 For the Client 1 For the Technician
- Used Technologies: MVVM with Modularization Compose Rest APIs with Retrofit & Gson Serialization Navigation Component Kotlin Coroutines with Flows

Islami 180| 🔊 📥

- Islamic application contains: Quran + Quran Tafseer Prayer Azan Qibla Finder Azkar Hijri Calendar Tasbeeh
- Used Technologies: MVVM Room database (for Quarn data storage) Retrofit (for prayer azan API requests) Android navigation component Json to Gson serialization Work Manager Notifications Manager Alarm Manager Senesor Manager And more

Zakerly 😱 📥

- Zakerly is an app used to connect students with teachers to learn online as an E-learning service And helps them attending online sessions individuals or groups
- Used Technologies: MVVM Firebase Kit (real time database & cloud messaging) Realm database (for data storage)
 Retrofit (for FCM API requests) Android navigation component Json to Gson serialization Jitsi meet sdk

iOS Projects

Whizzy | 🗯

- **Description**: Whizzy is a revolutionary mobile application designed to simplify the process of renting electric cars for short rides. With its user-friendly interface and advanced features, Whizzy aims to provide a modern and convenient solution for urban commuters looking for eco-friendly transportation options.
- **Used Technologies**: MVVM architecture with Swift UI, Alamofire for networking, Kingfisher for image loading, Combine GCD for asynchronous programming.

Pet Matrices | A (

- Pet Matrices is a lifestyle application for your pets where you can record and track your pets activities and given calories, you also can record and track their health condition and get some nice advice from an expert
- Used Technologies: SwiftUI, REST API, MVVM archticture pattern, Swift GCD

Memorise 🕠 🐞

Memorising game created with swift and Swift UI.
 A project for Stanford CS193p course at: https://cs193p.sites.stanford.edu/

■ Kotlin Multiplatform Projects

Masarify | **K**

- Innovative expenses tracker App
- leveraging Kotlin Multiplatform (KMP) for seamless development across multiple platforms. Demonstrated proficiency
 in KMP, delivering a feature-rich application with multi-account support, dynamic categories, and multi-currency support.
- Used Technologies: MVVM -Compose multiplatform- SQLDelight KTor Voyager Router KotlinX Serialization -KAMEL

Ion K

- Residential compound community app that also shows the developer other compounds.
- Online-based, leveraging Kotlin Multiplatform (KMP) for seamless development across multiple platforms.
- Used Technologies: MVVM Compose multiplatform KTor Voyager KotlinX Serialization KAMEL

More Projects at my GitHub O